# 大家好 你看 這裡有幾棵這個 攀蒲苗
Hi everyone! Look! Here are some, this kind of, pumpkin seedlings.
# 我挖到下面去種哦 要不然就被雞踩死啦
I'm gonna dig them out and plant them down there. Otherwise the chickens would step on them.
# 這個挖出來
Let me dig it out.
# 這也有一棵
Here's another one.
# 4棵
Four,
# 種4棵就夠啦
planting four would be enough.
# 就種這幾棵就夠啦
I'll plant only these seedlings here.
# 這還有西紅杮哦 西紅杮我也種一棵
Here are also tomatoes. I'm gonna plant one tomato there too.
# 這西紅杮好大棵了 現在
This tomato is really big now.
# 這兩棵都比較大的 把它挖過去
These two are larger than the others. Let me take them there.
# 好 就種這幾棵
Alright! I'll plant these over there.
# 我們不挖走的話就沒有啦
Nothing would be left if we keep them here.
# 是不是有個葛根
Is here a kudzu root?
# 沒有
No
# 搞到下面去種
Let me plant them down there.
# 這裡種
Let me plant,
# 種兩棵番茄
plant two tomatoes here.
# 這裡來種
Plant them here.
# 你看 這些 這番茄我看它長得
Look! These, these tomatoes, I think they're really,
# 長勢是最大的
their growth is much ahead of the others.
# 嗯 還有一棵 哎喲
Um? There should be one more. Ayo!
# 我以為壓死啦
I thought it was crushed.
# 沒壓死
No, it isn't.
# 這樣 雙胞胎 剛好它們有伴
They are twins from now on. It's good that they have a buddy,
# 一人一邊
and have their own share of space.
# 等下我過來澆一下水
I'll water them in a while.
# 再種一棵攀蒲 這裡
Let me plant a pumpkin as well, here.
# 我把它攀蒲種在這裡
I'll plant the pumpkin here.
# 攀蒲肯定會長很多攀蒲出來的
Pumpkins, I'm sure that there will be a lot of pumpkins.
# 可以 先種在這裡
Yup. Let me plant them here first.
# 到時候到秋天的時候就好多
Later, in autumn, there will be a lot,
# 好多東西吃
a lot of good food.
# 又有攀蒲
Not only pumpkins,
# 又有西紅杮
but also tomatoes.
# 再種好一棵
So one more is planted.
# 這裡再種一棵
Let me plant one more here.
# 嗯 又種好一棵
Um! Another one is planted.
# 這裡可以種一棵
I can plant one more here.
# 這個攀蒲是以前那個豬
These pumpkins are grown from the seeds,
# 吃剩下的那個籽
in the leftover of the pigs,
# 長出來啦
which used to be here.
# 最後一棵
The last one
# 嗯 等下澆一下水
Um! Let me water them in a while.
# 有個刺啊 這裡
A splinter
# 好啦 已經種下去啦
Alright! So they're all planted.
# 給它們澆一下水
I'll water them.
# 拿個盆子來 (註︰結果他拿來了一個桶，我是不會為他更正的)
Let me fetch a bowl.
# 夠啦
It's enough.
# 這裡還有那麼多
Here's still a lot.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 到時候我們就有 (註︰「到時候」譯作"later"較合適，但若把"later"放在前面又不太自然，放在後面又不合這裡的情景和分句，所以改了一下)
In a few months, we can,
# 攀蒲吃啦
enjoy our pumpkins.
# 這上次種的那個蘭花都活啦
The orchids that I planted last time is now growing pretty well.